Nero...
ネロ
Starting today, I'll be your brother.
今日からは俺が兄弟だ
kanjou ni tsukeru
I can assign whatever name I wish
namae wa jiyuu dane
To these emotions.
hora kawarihateta
See, they've already ceased to change.
kesenai boku no
The trigger of
tsumi no hikigane ga
My unrepentable sins
toketeshimaisou de
Seems ready to melt away,
nikushimi ga kieteshimattara
But if this hatefulness fades,
kimi o korosenai kara
I'll lose my chance to kill you.
kako o tannou shiteiru
I'm experiencing every moment of my past,
tsumi ga tsukutta boku ni kawaru tame ni
Trying to become the person who created these sins
ASL no naifu de
With an ASL knife.
kioku no signal kizamareteru noni
Despite the signal carved into my memories,
itami sae keshisatteshimau kizuna no spiral
Even the pain is erased away by this spiral of causality.
Having wandered in, I begin to fade... ceasing to be myself.
mayoikonda boku wa boku de kietekureteiku
Behind the Curtain
幕後
This is Mr. Delphy of the Federal
Bureau of Prohibition from Chicago.
シカゴから来た連邦取締官のデルフィ氏だ
He'll be keeping the peace in
this city from now on in my place.
今後は私に代わって 彼がこの町の平和を守ることになる
Mr. Delphy, why have you come to this town?
デルフィさん なぜこの町へ
There's a rotten stench in this town,
この町には 悪臭が漂っている
and it's coming from the mafia.
そしてその匂いの元はマフィア共だ
I'm here to end the age of the
police serving as their faithful dogs.
警察が奴等の犬であった時代は私が終わらせる
What exactly do you mean by the mafia?
マフィアって具体的には?
First, the Fango family.
まずは ファンゴ ファミリー
Fango became don in place of Orco,
オルコに変わってドンとなったファンゴは
and is now working with influential
people in the city to expand his power.
町の有力者と手を結んで 勢力を広げている
Then there's the Island, their home base.
そして 奴等のアジトである アイランド
It's become a hive for evil.
あそここそが 悪の巣窟
I'm going to sweep it away.
私が一掃してみせる
Next, the Vanetti family that has
controlled this city for many years.
次に この町を古くから牛耳るヴァネッティ ファミリー
They finally put an end to their internal feud, right?
内部抗争がやっと終わりましたね
Right now, the acting don of the Vanetti
family is Vincent's eldest son, Nero.
今や実質的なドンはヴィンセントの長男 ネロだ
The moonshine they make, Lawless Heaven,
奴等が密造してるローレス ヘブンは
has been fetching high prices
domestically and internationally of late.
近頃国内外で高値で取引されている
Nero's a popular guy around here though.
でも ネロはこの町の人気者ですよ
Much more popular than you cops.
警察よりずっとね
They're trash, sucking out the blood of law-abiding citizens.
奴等は 市民の生き血を吸うクズ共だ
I'm going to unmask the beast.
今に化けの皮を剥がしてやる
両ファミリーの勢力争いで
The power struggle between the two families
is endangering public order in the city.
町の治安は著しく悪化している
私は...いや
I... No, we of the police will first crack
down on the brewing of moonshine,
我々警察は まず密造酒を取り締まり
cutting off their source of income.
奴等の収入源を断つ
そして 善良な市民の為
Then, for the good people of this city,
we will eradicate every one—
必ず奴等を一掃することを...
What a blowhard.
暑苦しい野郎だ
It might be best to cut down on
Lawless Heaven production for a while.
暫く ローレスヘブンの生産は抑えた方が良さそうだな
No, keep it rolling out.
いや どんどん作れ
The sinners are waiting, after all.
罪深い市民が待ってるからな
Bet he's got a big dick.
アソコがデカそうな顔だ
A big nose means a big dick.
鼻がでげぇとアソコもでげぇんだ
He looks like the straight-laced, stubborn type, though.
しかしその鼻デカ 融通が利かね堅物野郎だとか
Guys like him are easy to deal with.
そういう奴程扱いやすい
I think it's about time...
そろそろかもな
Huh?
はい?
To crush the Vanettis.
ヴァネッティを潰す頃合いだ
Hey, aren't you...
あんた確か...
Delphy, of the Federal Bureau of Prohibition.
連邦取締官のデルフィだ
Look at that.
見てくれ
Mr. Delphy, I'm with you.
デルフィさん わしはあんたを支持する
I'm sick of violence.
暴力はウンザリだ
That's reassuring to hear.
そう言ってくれると 心強いよ
We're counting on you. As soon as possible—
頼んだぞ 一日も早く...
What do Vanetti's dogs want with me?
ヴァネッティの犬がなんの用だ
What's this?
なんだこれは
You just moved here so I'm sure you have a lot of expenses.
越してきたばかりだと 色々物言いだろう
Keep your dirty money.
汚い金は締まってくれ
Your daughter is four years old now, right?
娘さん 確か4歳だったよな
You ought to take care of your family.
家族は大事にしないとな
You forgot this.
忘れもんだ
ネロ ヴァネッティに伝えろ
Tell Nero Vanetti that I will
crush him, no matter what.
必ず潰してやるとな
You even dug up info on his family?
家族のことまで調べ上げるとはね
You've grown comfortable in the mafia...
すっかりマフィアが板についてきたじゃないか
That big-nosed freak...
あの鼻デカ野郎
What's wrong?
どうした
"Delphy exposes multiple
establishments selling bootleg liquor."
デルフィン氏、密造酒販売店を連日摘発する
He's messing with us.
舐めやがって
Nero, more and more bars are passing on buying our liquor.
ネロ 酒の仕入れを渋る店が増えて来てる
Fire two or three rounds into big-nose's house.
この鼻デカの家に二三発打ち込め
If that doesn't work, rub him out.
それで駄目なら やっちまえ
本字幕由✿花語&千夏字幕組✿共同製作
Hey, Nero.
おい ネロ
It's really affecting him...
大分 引きずってるな
What do you expect?
しょうがねだろう
Nice weather, huh?
いい天気だな
Want to go for a drive?
ドライブでも行くか?
Sorry, but I've decided to never
get in a car you're driving again.
悪いが お前の運転する車には二度と乗らねって決めってんだ
Fango will make a move soon.
ファンゴはそのうち仕掛けてくる
We'd best move cautiously from now on.
これからは 慎重に動いたほうがいい
I'm the only one left.
もう俺しかいね
I have to protect the family.
俺がファミリを守るんだ
To make that happen, I...
そのためなら 俺は
Will you come with me?
ついてきてくれるか
Yeah.
I never thought you'd join the mafia, though.
しっかし お前がマフィアなるとはな
It's unbelievable.
まさかの展開だぜ
"I hate the mafia" used to be your tune.
マフィアは嫌いなんだとか 言ってたくせによ
I still hate them.
今でも嫌いさ
Corteo.
コルテオ
The truth is, Fango wants you.
実はファンゴさんがお前をほしがってんだわ
ここだけの話
This doesn't leave this room,
but I hear Prohibition's ending soon.
禁酒法は近々終わるらしい
Someone heard a bigshot talking about it.
どっかのお偉いさんから聞いた情報だ
そうなるや 誰でも簡単に買えるようになる
Then anyone will be able to buy it with no problem just like before.
昔みてぇにな
ファンゴさんは そん時に備えて
Fango wants some really good booze to prepare for that day.
まじで旨い酒を欲しがってる
That's why he needs you!
そこでお前の力が必要って訳だ
Having someone like him
acknowledge you is pretty amazing!
あの人に認められるなんて すげぇじゃねか
I'll pass.
辞めとくと
What?! Why? It's your chance to be rich!
なんでだ 金持ちになれるチャンスなんだぞ
Is that true?
本当だろうな?
Yeah, I swear to God.
神に誓うぜ
Don't worry. This isn't a trade-off.
安心しろ こりゃ取引じゃね
It's just a tip.
ただの情報提供だ
What? The Lodge is...
へ ロッジが...
Delphy's investigating it.
デルフィの捜査が入った
That bastard!
あの野郎
Take out his family.
奴の家族をやれ
Can't we just take him out?
本人だけで十分だ
No.
いやだ
Then someone else would pick up the investigation.
それじゃ 誰かが捜査を引き継ぐだけだ
He's right.
そうだ
We need Delphy himself to call it off.
デルフィ自身に捜査を打ち切らせるんだ
Let's take a break.
休憩にしよう
That reminds me. I'm taking my family out for a picnic soon.
そういや 今度家族連れてピクニックへ行くんですが
Want to come?
どうです
No, I'd like to, but I can't.
いいえ 行きたいが さすがに無理だ
Yeah, I'll bet.
ですよね
I'd love to get out with the family soon, though.
そろそろ 家族揃って出かけたいよ
I'll invite you next time, too.
まだ 誘いますよ
Sure.
You've got to be kidding!
いい加減にしろよ
What do you think you're doing?
どういうつもりなんだ
Going after the guy's family...
家族にまで手を出すなんて
Isn't your revenge against the Vanettis?
復讐の相手はバネッチィのやつらだろう
What is this?
なんだ これ
You wanted to go to college, didn't you?
学校 行きたっかたんだろう
Stay out of my life from now on.
もう 俺に関わるな
You're the one who dragged me into this!
お前が巻き込んだじゃないか
Where's my teddy?
テディは
Hey, where'd my teddy go?
ね デディどこに行ったか知らない...
Hello?
もしもし
Call off the investigation at once.
今すぐ捜査を中止しろ
I won't respond to threats!
私には脅しには屈しない
This is your last warning.
最後の忠告だ
I refuse!
断る
Don't make me say it again!
何度も言わせるな
You work too much, dear.
You should take some time off.
あなた働き過ぎよ 少しは休んで
Yeah.
Take care of them.
頼んだぞ
Sir.
はい
Papa, aren't you coming?
パパ来ないの
Do what your mom tells you, okay?
母さんの言うこと よく聞くんだぞ
We'll get going now.
もう行くわね
Yeah.
Yes?
はい
You're sure about that info?
その情報は確かなんだろうな
You surprised me, though.
しかし驚きだぜ
Never thought you'd come to me with this.
まさかお前から こんな話が聞けるとはなぁ
Damn it...
ったく
This is how it always ends up.
結局いつもこうなるんだ
Delphy's taken care of.
デルフィの件は片付いた
They'll leave the Lodge alone.
ロッジにも目を瞑ると
Good.
Can't believe they called us out
here just to check the carpet color.
わざわざ呼び出されてカーペットの色かよ
Hey.
Don't come any closer.
それ以上近寄るな
Hey... You're Nero Vanetti, right?
あの ネロ ヴァネッティさんですよね
I'm such a fan of yours!
俺 あんたのファンなんだ
Oh, yeah? Glad to hear it.
そうかい そいつありがとうよ
Wait... Come on, hear me out!
ちょっと なぁ 話聞いてくれよ
Let me join the family! Okay?
俺をファミリーに入れてくれ ねぇ
Hey! Take a hike.
おぃ さっさと消えろう
Come on, don't brush me off!
そんな冷てぇこと言わねぇでよ
Nero!
ネロ
It's Fango!
ファンゴだ
He set the whole thing up!
とうとう仕掛けてきやがった
Very few people knew Nero would be here today.
しかし 今日ネロがここに来ることを知っていたのは限られた人間だけだ
Find the traitor.
探せ 裏切り者
Calm down.
落ち着け
How can I calm down?
落ち着ける訳無いだろう
Listen up, Corty-baby.
いいかコルテオちゃん
We'd love to take you in at our place,
お前をうちで匿うのは お安い御用だ
でもよ
but then they'd know you're the one who betrayed them.
それじゃ裏切り者がお前だってばれちまう
Drink some of this and calm down.
これでも飲んで落ち着け
俺達は次こそネロをやる
We'll kill Nero next time.
Then the Vanettis will be through.
そしたらヴァネッティは終わりだ
お前はうちで酒を作って がっぽり稼げばいい
You can make booze with us and make loads of cash. Everybody's happy.
皆パッピーだ
Happy?
ハッピー?
Yeah... Happy!
そう パーピー
Show a little enthusiasm, boy!
乗り悪いな ボーイ
Anyway, about the booze...
あ それで良い 酒のことなんだが
Hey, you gonna walk home?
おぃ 歩いて帰るのか
Everyone only cares about themselves...
どいつも こいつも 自分のことばっかだ
So this is what "high alert" looks like.
厳戒態勢ってやつか?
Hey, stop! You can't!
ちょっと 駄目ですよ
Nero, it's me!
ネロ 俺だ
I gotta talk to you! Open up!
話がある 開けろう
What is it, kid? I didn't come here to talk to you.
何だ 洟垂れ お前に用はねぇ
No one's allowed to see Nero right now.
今は誰もネロとは会えない
Listen, kid. How many years do you think I've been here?
おぃ ガキ 俺がここに何年いると思ってんだ
Before Nero was even born—
ネロが生まれる前...
叔父貴
Uncle.
I'm very sorry.
申し訳ありません
Don't let anyone in.
誰も入れるなぁ
Corteo.
コルテオ
We're done for.
参ったよ
We won't be able to come back here for a while.
しばらく ここへ顔を出せそうにない
Well? Did you find who did it?
どう 目星はついたの
Everyone's a suspect.
まあ 全員が容疑者みたいなもんだ
Me and you, too.
俺とお前もなぁ
Well, you can leave this place to me.
まあ ここは僕に任せてよ
Sure, thanks.
あぁ 助かるよ
Learn everyone's names. That's the first step.
名前を覚えわ 先ずそっからだ
Right.
はい
If you need to piss, knock.
小便行きたくなったら ノックだ
Is this the list of invitees?
招待客の名簿は
All of them, excluding those who haven't replied yet.
向こうの返事待ちを除けばこれで全部だ
I don't recognize most of them. Will it be okay?
知らね名前だらけだ 大丈夫なのか
I vetted them before inviting them.
ちゃんと調べて呼んでる
Don't worry.
心配するな
Well?
どうだぁ
N-Nice swing!
ナイス スイングです
I meant Corteo! Has he sent anymore info on Nero?
コルテオのことだ ネロの情報が来たか
Sorry, sir... Not yet.
すいあせん まだ何も
Darling, you have an unusual visitor.
ダーリン 珍しいお客よ
You're still in this town?
まだこの町にいたのか
Thought you got replaced as head of the Bureau.
元取締官殿
Thank you for asking. I've been reinstated.
お陰様で 復職することになりましてね
What a surprise. Is that you, Cerotto?
驚いたなあ チェロットじゃないか
N-Nice to see you, Mr. Scusa.
ど...どうも スクーザさん
So you were here, huh?
ここにいたんだ
Y-Yeah...
え ええ まあ...
Good stuff.
気に入ったぜ
Well? What are you going to do about Corteo?
で コルテオの方はどうするんです
He knows entirely too much.
あいつは色々知り過ぎだ
Why's he calling me out here at this time of night?
こんな時間に呼び出してなんの用だよ
You're being awfully quiet tonight.
今夜はやけに静かじゃないか
The city's gotten too dangerous lately.
最近 この町も物騒んなってきたよなぁ
このままシカゴにでも行っちまうか
Hey, you want to just go to Chicago?
禁止法もあるし
Prohibition's on the way out. As long as we have the recipe, it'll take no time to...
レシピさえありゃ あっという間に...
What are you talking about?
一体何の話だよ
It's no use. You stink to high heaven of booze.
だめだ 酒臭くてたまんなねわ
You're gonna get me drunk.
こっちは酔っちまうぜ
Welcome to my castle!
ウェルカム トゥ マイ キャッスル
Well? Want a drink?
どうだい 一杯やるか
What did you want to talk about?
その 話って...
I'll keep it brief.
簡潔に話そう
I'm through working with you.
俺はお前と組むのをやめた
To be frank, I've got no more use for you.
正直言ってお前にはもう使い道がない
But... my alcohol?
でも酒は
Didn't you want my alcohol?
僕の酒が欲しいんじゃねえのか?
Have a drink first and calm down.
先ず一杯飲んで落ち着き
Lawless Heaven?
ローレス ヘブン
Look.
ほら
The recipe...
レシピ
It was Scusa.
スクーザだ
He copied it from what that big-nose confiscated.
奴は鼻デカが押収した時に書き写したんだ
He even made me a real nice sample.
そしてご丁寧にサンプルまで造ってきやがった
You can't beat that kick!
このキックはまさにだ
But seriously, that guy is human garbage.
しかしおよ アイツ本当人間のクズだぜ
Tried to charge me out the nose for it.
こいつをとんでもない高値で売りつけてきやがって
The point is, I don't need you anymore.
まあ とにかく もうお前なんてどうでもいい
Forget it, just get lost.
まあいいや さっさと消えろ
Maybe I'll tell Nero-baby who the real traitor is instead.
その代わり裏切り者の正体をネロちゃんに教えてあげるかなぁ
Hey, operator! Get me the Vanetti mansion.
おう 交換手 バネッチィの屋敷だ
Put me through to Nero Vanetti.
ネロ バネッチィに繋いでくれ
What's that?
何だ
Me? My name is Fango!
俺? 俺の名前はファンゴだ
Where'd you go? Can't see...
どこへ行った 見えね
That feels pretty damn good, boy...
気持ちいいじゃねえか ボーイ